<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Redshiftzero</title>
    <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/categories/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Redshiftzero</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://redshiftzero.github.io/categories/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using pyreverse to general UML class diagrams</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/pyreverse-uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/pyreverse-uml/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wanted to generate UML (Unified Modeling Language) diagrams of the structure of an existing codebase for the purpose of having an architecture discussion.
I was wondering if there was a tool to generate UML diagrams in Python to save me some manual work.
Enter pyreverse: it comes installed with pylint which is a very common development dependency in Python. pyreverse enables you to point to the code you want UML diagrams of, here in my example I was generating a diagram of a project called securedrop-export:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging programs with pdb</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/pdb-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/pdb-debugging/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to try my hand at making YouTube videos. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on mostly making videos about topics I commonly find myself explaining to people, so here&amp;rsquo;s the first, on using pdb, the built-in debugger in the Python standard library.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for handling flaky test suites</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/test-flakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/test-flakes/</guid>
      <description>Test flakes are tests that occasionally fail due to a variety of potential reasons including network instability (for tests making network calls that are not mocked) and other non-deterministic behavior. Test flakes are problematic as they reduce confidence in the results of test runs: they condition developers that the test suite cannot be relied on, and as such can result in legitimate bugs being ignored due to alert fatigue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision attacks and the birthday paradox</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/birthday-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/birthday-attacks/</guid>
      <description>How many people do you need in a room before there is a 50% chance that least two of them share the same birthday? It&amp;rsquo;s only 23, though unless you have heard about this paradox before, you might expect it to be much larger. This is the well-known birthday paradox: it&amp;rsquo;s called a paradox only because collisions happen much faster than one naively expects. Collisions here means an event where two or more observed values are equal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Publishing Data on ICE Employees is in the Public Interest</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/publishing-public-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/publishing-public-interest/</guid>
      <description>This was written with Camille Fassett and first appeared on the website of the Lucy Parsons Labs.
Motivated by the Trump administration’s policy of detaining and separating migrant children from their families at the border, artist and developer Sam Lavigne harvested profiles that list Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) as an employer on social network LinkedIn.
He made the dataset of all 1595 responsive profiles, which included names, titles, photographs and general locations, available to download on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Cosmological Power Spectra with d3.js</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/visualizing-cosmological-power-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/visualizing-cosmological-power-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Cosmologists make observations of galaxies and radiation in the universe to constrain parameters of the Lambda CDM model , which is the model that best describes our current understanding of the universe. These cosmological parameters include quantities like &amp;Omega;m and &amp;Omega;&amp;Lambda;, which describe the matter and dark energy content of the universe respectively.
Two key observables that constrain these parameters are the matter power spectrum and the angular power spectrum of the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) radiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primer on Police Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/police-surveillance-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/police-surveillance-primer/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a short primer describing and visualizing police surveillance technology. This project was also posted on the website of the Lucy Parsons Labs.

Cameras, automatic license plate readers, cell site simulators and many other surveillance devices are currently used in the city by the Chicago Police Department and its sister agencies. However, many citizens are unaware of the scope of the surveillance systems, their huge cost, and the privacy implications of their use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>