<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redshiftzero</title>
    <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redshiftzero</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://redshiftzero.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Publishing Data on ICE Employees is in the Public Interest</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/publishing-public-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/publishing-public-interest/</guid>
      <description>This was written with Camille Fassett and first appeared on the website of the Lucy Parsons Labs.
Motivated by the Trump administration’s policy of detaining and separating migrant children from their families at the border, artist and developer Sam Lavigne harvested profiles that list Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) as an employer on social network LinkedIn.
He made the dataset of all 1595 responsive profiles, which included names, titles, photographs and general locations, available to download on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Cosmological Power Spectra with d3.js</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/visualizing-cosmological-power-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/visualizing-cosmological-power-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Cosmologists make observations of galaxies and radiation in the universe to constrain parameters of the Lambda CDM model , which is the model that best describes our current understanding of the universe. These cosmological parameters include quantities like &amp;Omega;m and &amp;Omega;&amp;Lambda;, which describe the matter and dark energy content of the universe respectively.
Two key observables that constrain these parameters are the matter power spectrum and the angular power spectrum of the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) radiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How SecureDrop Works 101</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/securedrop-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/securedrop-101/</guid>
      <description>When people first learn of the SecureDrop architecture, it can seem quite complicated. When explaining SecureDrop to people for the first time, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to have a cartoon view providing a broad overview before digging into further technical details (in my experience this is true of any sufficiently technical concept/system). After noticing this confusion from users, I made this quick one-minute video to distill the most important points for the source and journalist workflows:</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Chicago Police Department&#39;s Secret Budget</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/cpd-asset-forfeiture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/cpd-asset-forfeiture/</guid>
      <description>Every year, police take millions of dollars from Chicagoans through civil asset forfeiture and spend it behind closed doors. In collaboration with Muckrock, my co-authors and I did an independent financial audit of this previously undocumented part of the police budget. We demonstrated these asset forfeiture funds are used to circumvent city council oversight and finance controversial surveillance devices. This investigation appeared as a front page feature in the September 29, 2016 issue of the Chicago Reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Primer on Police Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/police-surveillance-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/police-surveillance-primer/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a short primer describing and visualizing police surveillance technology. This project was also posted on the website of the Lucy Parsons Labs.

Cameras, automatic license plate readers, cell site simulators and many other surveillance devices are currently used in the city by the Chicago Police Department and its sister agencies. However, many citizens are unaware of the scope of the surveillance systems, their huge cost, and the privacy implications of their use.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
