<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal on Redshiftzero</title>
    <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/tags/signal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Signal on Redshiftzero</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://redshiftzero.github.io/tags/signal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Signal Protocol, Part 3: Web applications</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-webapps/</guid>
      <description>Next in the series, I investigate current messaging applications that both provide web applications and are using the Signal Protocol (or a protocol very similar or derived from Signal), here specifically Wire and Whatsapp. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking into the voice and video aspects, just the messaging and file sharing capabilities as I&amp;rsquo;m investigating to see how a similar approach could be used for SecureDrop, where voice/video isn&amp;rsquo;t an option. As always, if you have thoughts on this or notice errors, feel free to drop me a note on Twitter or by email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Signal Protocol, Part 2: Groups, devices</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-group-multidevice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-group-multidevice/</guid>
      <description>Next in the series, I investigate how groups and multi-device support are handled. If you have thoughts on this or notice any errors, feel free to drop me a note on Twitter or by email.
Groups Signal allows private groups where the server doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to the group metadata, including the list of members in each group. Servers cannot even distinguish group from direct messages.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say a group contains two users, Alice👧🏼 and Bob👦🏽, and a third user Jen🧙 wants to send the group a message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Signal Protocol, Part 1: Foundations</title>
      <link>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redshiftzero.github.io/signal-protocol/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been investigating applications that use the Signal Protocol in order to determine if the Signal Protocol for asynchronous messaging might be appropriate for use for applying to SecureDrop messaging in the future. In this post are some notes from reading the Signal Protocol specifications, which I thought might be a useful reference and explanation for others. If you notice an error, or have other thoughts on anything here, feel free to drop me a note on Twitter or by email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>